therockfather.com 2018-12-28

# The Rock Father: Privacy Policy

Updated May 25, 2018

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE RELATED TERMS OF SERVICE CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS WEBSITE.

**THE ROCK FATHER™**  respects the privacy concerns of all users. Protection of personal and sensitive information is paramount. This Privacy Policy discloses what type of information is collected, the method used to collect it and how THE ROCK FATHER utilizes the information to better serve all interested parties. Your use of THE ROCK FATHER website constitutes acceptance of this Privacy Policy and any other applicable terms. The Terms of Service for this website are hereby incorporated by reference.

**For European Visitors -  GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation):** The Rock Father Magazine uses [Quantcast Choice](https://www.quantcast.com/gdpr/quantcastchoice/), a consent management tool for publishers and advertisers built on the [IAB Europe Transparency & Consent Framework](https://advertisingconsent.eu/). When visiting this site, periodically you may be presented with a pop-up message inviting you to opt-in for data sharing. 

Quite simply, aside from cookies and limited information that you would voluntarily provide (detailed further below on this page), The Rock Father™ Magazine does not store your personal information and has no interest in doing so. We do not allow user accounts (hence no login needed), currently send no newsletters (we may eventually, which you would opt-in to, should that occur) and only pass-through limited, non-personally-identifiable data to gauge demographics, interests, readership location, etc. That said, many third-parties do collect certain data (advertisers, comment providers like Disqus, contest partners like Rafflecopter, etc.) and each has their own privacy policy and opt-in procedures. When you choose to opt-in via the pop-up box, those will be covered or be able to be excluded thanks to the advanced settings. 

**Children**

Protecting the privacy of children is especially important. We recognize the importance of safeguarding the privacy of children and encourage parents to check and monitor their children’s use of online activities regularly. The Rock Father website supports and complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) and other laws. The Rock Father website is not aimed at nor intended for children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not use The Rock Father website. Our website does not accept registration from children under the age of 13. No personally identifiable information (as defined in the COPPA, 15 U.S.C. Section 6501) is purposefully or knowingly collected from children under the age of 13 by The Rock Father without parental consent. Every user hereby agrees that all information you provide, including but not limited to age, shall be truthful and correct. The Rock Father will not condition a child’s participation in an online activity on the child providing more personally identifiable information than is reasonably necessary for participation in such activity.

**Information We Collect**

The Rock Father gathers, analyzes and/or stores personal information generally by way of three different sources: (1) the personal information voluntarily submitted by visitors when using or registering to use our services; (2) the personal and contact information visitors voluntarily provide when participating in any contests, sweepstakes and/or other promotions; (3)  by analyzing data through mechanisms that identify site usage, browser types, IP servers, etc. The Rock Father strives to provide our visitors with information relevant to their particular desires, needs and/or concerns. The information we gather helps us to better serve our purpose.

**General Data**  
General data includes information about you such as your name, address, email, and preferences. This information is generally gathered when you voluntarily submit the information to The Rock Father for purposes of, including but not limited to, registering for giveaways/contests, using comment forms (possibly third-party) or because you wish The Rock Father to provide you with our products, services or information. Such information allows The Rock Father to personalize your experience and helps The Rock Father better understand the demographics of our audience.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small piece of information sent to your computer’s browser, which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. There are two kinds of cookies The Rock Father operates: those that are “session” oriented and those that are “expiration” oriented. Session cookies delete from your computer at the moment you close your browser. Conversely, expiration cookies can be programmed to expire at any time; therefore when you close your browser, the cookie will remain on your hard drive until its expiration. Should you wish to be notified of, or to accept or decline cookies from being stored on your hard drive, please refer to your internet help directions.

To better provide you with excellent service, we may use cookies to remember information about your activities on our website.

**Non Identifying Information**

The Rock Father gathers and analyzes non-identifying user information such as Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses and browser types. Your IP address is an identifying number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. This number is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you visit the Site, along with the time(s) of your visit(s) and the page(s) that you visited. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice on the internet and is done automatically by many websites. In order to better aim our application efforts, we may record and tally information for the purpose of, including but not limited to, measuring our traffic and determining the origin of the audience.

**External Links**

The Rock Father may contain links to, or advertisements about, non-Rock Father websites. Other sites may also reference, advertise, or link to The Rock Father. The Rock Father does not endorse or sponsor other websites, is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of non-Rock Father sites, expressly disclaims any statements or assertions made on such websites, and denies all liability associated with your use of, and the content on, such other websites and advertisements.

**Consent to Processing in the United States**

By providing any personally identifiable information to The Rock Father, all users, including, without limitation, users in the member states of the European Union, fully understand and unambiguously consent to this Privacy Policy and to the collection, storage and processing of such information in the United States.

**Sharing Information**

The Rock Father does not buy or sell consumer information. We use and disclose information as explained in this policy and as required by law. In certain instances we may need to disclose user information to third parties relating to advertising, contest/sweepstakes requirements and/or winner verification. In this case, the user may be given the option to receive additional materials from these companies. You have the choice to either accept or decline the invitation.

**Advertising**

THE ROCK FATHER works with third party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our Web site.  These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g. click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you.  These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information.  To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice visit the NAI at[](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)[http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).  To opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit[](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)<http://www.aboutads.info/choices>.  

**Comment Sections  
**

The Rock Father retains the right to control conversations through our comment sections, whether provided directly by The Rock Father or through a third-party. By this we mean controlling profanity, illegal use, etc, but reserve the right to moderate comments in any way or for any reason we see fit. By using our comment sections, you are voluntarily giving us the right to publicize the contents of your interactions. Please do not use our comment sections if you do not wish your interactions to be public. The Rock Father encourages use of real names in the comment sections, and may use the information that you have voluntarily provided (such as email addresses) to verify identity.

**Survey/Polls**

Periodically visitors may be asked to participate in surveys and/or polls. Participation is completely voluntary. Data collected from these surveys are analyzed for statistical purposes only.

**Sweepstakes/Contests**

The Rock Father may periodically run promotional sweepstakes and/or contests. Participation is completely voluntary. Additional information is generally required for purposes like, including but not limited to, determining eligibility and contacting potential winners. By participating in said promotions, you agree that your information be shared with sponsors for shipping purposes should you win. Guidelines explaining The Rock Father’s policies with respect to Sweepstakes/Contests are always posted along with sweepstakes information.

**Revisions to Privacy Policy**

By using the The Rock Father website, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended and/or revised at any time. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the The Rock Father website. The Rock Father reserves the right to change and/or amend this policy at any time without notification, which The Rock Father may provide to you by any reasonable means including, but not limited to, posting the revised policy on the The Rock Father website. Please note that you will always be able to determine if this Privacy Policy has been amended or updated since your last visit to our website by referring to the “Last Revised” legend at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the The Rock Father website subsequent to changes to the Privacy Policy will mean that you accept and agree to the revisions. For any questions, suggestions, or concerns please email james [at] therockfather.com[  
](mailto:info@corpka.com)
